<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Ohio Black Press in the 19th Century</title>
    <link>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The Ohio Black Press in the 19th Century</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Dec 2021 14:09:31 -0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/post/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>R Markdown This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com.
You can embed an R code chunk like this:
summary(cars) ## speed dist ## Min. : 4.0 Min. : 2.00 ## 1st Qu.:12.0 1st Qu.: 26.00 ## Median :15.0 Median : 36.00 ## Mean :15.4 Mean : 42.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/about/</guid>
      <description>About the Project This site is created to offer data visualizations and interactive maps of the Ohio Black press in the 19th century.
Contributors Jewon Woo, project director
Jason Heppler, senior web developer, RRCHNM</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data</title>
      <link>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/data/</guid>
      <description>fringilla potenti libero facilisis aptent. Vestibulum mi posuere</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the Advertisers Sold</title>
      <link>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/advertisements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/advertisements/</guid>
      <description>In addition to subscribers, advertisements in newspapers serve more than as a financial source to sustain these papers. They offer a picture of the society that publishers, editors, and readers shape together in the medium of commercial goods and services. In particular, Black newspapers suggest the ways in which African Americans participated in the American economy at the time when political denial of Black citizenship hampered their economic advancement as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the Editors Reprinted</title>
      <link>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/maps/</guid>
      <description>Reprinting pieces from other periodicals and published texts was a common practice in nineteenth century print culture. Many of Black newspapers did not have enough agents, correspondents, and resources to maintain profitable publications, relying heavily on other periodicals as alternative news sources for first-hand reports. In the case of the Black newspapers in this project, total 287 different periodicals were reprinted, quoted, or mentioned, often more than once, in sixty-five issues out of the fourteen newspapers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What the Subscribers Read</title>
      <link>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/topics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blacknewspapers.rrchnm.org/topics/</guid>
      <description>Topics in the newspapers hosted in this project show various aspects of early Black communities in Ohio. First, we can see what contemporary readers looked for in the newspaper. Their interests reveal the relationship that individual readers had with their community at familial, local, national, and even international levels. Second, newspaper topics tell what editors and publishers aimed at through its publication. Like most Black periodicals in the 19th century, publishing newspapers in Ohio was an unprofitable business, for which editors and publishers often had to maintain jobs other than working for the paper until Harry Smith as a full-time newspaperman started the Cleveland Gazette in 1883.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
